#### WEB DEVELOPER

Web Developer with over 17 years of web development experience (UI/UX, websites, web ads, SEO) and 10 years of web project management experience. An MFA in Creative Writing provides a unique combination of technological expertise and stellar communication skills. Passionate about creating logical and intuitive interfaces on the web regardless of the device used.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## • Front End Engineer

*October 2013 – Present* Spotify

- Work on a team that manages Spotify Radio on all platforms
- O Developing apps for the Spotify Desktop, Web, and Android Clients

# • Lead Front End Engineer

February 2013 – October 2013 Zeebox (zeebox.com) U.S.

- o Code HTML 5 Games, Responsive Websites, and other Javascript Applications
- Manage a group of mid-level developers
- Advise on best web practices, code management and versioning, cross-browser/cross-device compatibility, and browser memory management and optimization.

## • Senior Web Developer

February 2007 – February 2013

The City University of New York (CUNY) Office of Communications and Marketing

- o Team Leader of Central Office web team (developers, content editors, server admins)
- Develop for and maintain cuny.edu (10 million + page-views/month): XSL, XML, Javascript, PHP, MySQL, HTML 5, CSS3
- Manage university web projects: CUNY School of Law, CUNY School of Public Health, New Community College.

## Freelance Web Developer/Designer

October 2006 – Present

- o Over 20 clients in multiple industries.
- o Designed and Built Websites using Wordpress, Joomla, Drupal, Lenya.

#### Web Developer

*October 2005 – May 2007* Sarah Lawrence College

- o Manager of college web projects: content editing, site development, information architecture, client
- Developer: Online student applications and web tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, JSP.

## Web Developer

June 1997 – September 1999 UCLA Medical School

o Developer and Departmental Liaison: web content editing, development, and design.

# **LANGUAGES**

Javascript, Java, PHP, XSTL, Shell Scripting, MySQL, HTML, CSSS

## FRAMEWORKS & APPLICATIONS

NodeJS, Angular, Backbone, Grunt, Gulp, SOAP, AJAX, Wordpress, Drupal, Joomla, Lenya, Hippo, Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Suite, Github, SVN

## **SKILLS**

SEO, semantic markup, responsive design, accessibility standards, web performance optimization

# **EDUCATION AND HONORS**

B.A. in Literature 2003
University of California Santa Barbara
College of Creative Studies (www.ccs.ucsb.edu)

• M.F.A. in Creative Writing: Poetry May 2007 Sarah Lawrence College (www.slc.edu)

## FREELANCE WEB PROJECTS

www.cunyprep.org - www.changentcoaching.com - www.marinacooks.com - www.storyscapejournal.com - www.sethfenton.com - www.louderarts.com - www.citybankantiques.com - www.piquelearning.com - www.academyofcreativeeducation.com - www.millermenthelaw.com - www.melanierome.com - www.oralmalodor.com - www.unitednationsoffood.com - www.melanierome.com - www.cameronmcpherson.com